Inventory of the Kenneth Holland papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Kenneth Holland papers
1919-1996
2000C93
Holland, Kenneth.
62 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (25.2 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
The papers contain materials that largely relate to the subject of international education, with a special emphasis on the role played in this field by American institutions in the period after World War II. As the long-time head of the Institute of International Education (IIE), a private non-profit organization based in New York City, Holland was involved in the administration of student exchange programs on behalf of the United States government, including the important Fulbright Program. He also supervised a large number of research projects that evaluated education systems in different countries. His papers consist of his numerous speeches and articles on educational topics, as well as a great deal of correspondence, reports, and printed matter, much of it pertaining to his work at the IIE.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2000.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
1907 Born, Los Angeles
1929 Bachelor of Arts, Occidental College
1930 Master of Arts, Princeton University
1977 Died
1933-1935 Education director, Civilian Conservation Corps
1935-1941 Associate director, American Youth Commission, American Council on Education
1942-1945 Director, Education Division, Office of Inter-American Affairs
1946-1948 Assistant director, Office of International Information and Cultural Affairs, U.S. Department of State
1948-1950 U.S. representative, UNESCO
1950-1973 President, Institute of International Education
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers contain materials that largely relate to the subject of international education, with a special emphasis on the role played in this field by American institutions in the period after World War II. As the longtime head of the Institute of International Education (IIE), a private non-profit organization based in New York City, Holland was involved in the administration of student exchange programs on behalf of the United States government, including the important Fulbright Program. He also supervised a large number of research projects that evaluated education systems in different countries. His papers consist of his numerous speeches and articles on educational topics, as well as a great deal of correspondence, reports, and printed matter, much of it pertaining to his work at the IIE.
Holland traveled extensively in his capacity as head of the IIE and as an acknowledged expert on educational matters. He was part of the official delegation that accompanied President Eisenhower on his tour of Latin America in 1960, and he again visited the region as a member of the Rockefeller Mission to Latin America in 1969. He traveled several times to the Soviet Union, and made working trips to Africa, Asia, and Europe. The papers include country briefings and numerous reports produced for the Rockefeller Mission, as well as extensive documentation of his other foreign travels. Holland also attended numerous conferences devoted to international education, and the collection includes many of the speeches and papers that he delivered at such gatherings.
The IIE materials in the papers include routine correspondence, minutes of trustees meetings, as well as many reports published by the organization. In addition, there are drafts of a history of the IIE written by Holland. The collection also contains materials on conferences held under the auspices of the IIE, including those organized by a subsidiary of the IIE, the Council on Higher Education in the Americas. Some IIE materials were added to the collection after Holland's death.
Early in his career, Holland worked for the American Council on Education, where he contributed to a history of the Civilian Conservation Corps in the United States. He also authored an international study of youth labor camps established by various governments during the Depression. The papers contain his writings and research materials on these subjects. During 1948-1950, Holland served as the United States representative to UNESCO, and there are some materials relating to this experience in the papers. There are also drafts of chapters of Holland's autobiography in the collection.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Civilian Conservation Corps (U.S.); United States. Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs.; United States. Dept. of State. Office of International Information and Cultural Affairs.; Institute of International Education (New York, N.Y.); Unesco. Office of International Information and Cultural Affairs.; International education.; Student exchange programs.; Work camps.; United States Relations.; United States Relations Latin America.; Latin America Relations United States.
Collection Contents
- Institute of International Education (IIE) materials, 1949-1974 (Box 1:)
  - Priorities, 1966-1967 (Folder 1: 1)
  - Bulletins, pamphlet, and invitation, 1949-1974 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Correspondence and memoranda, 1966-1974 (Folder 1: 3)
- Other printed matter relating to international education, 1964-1977 (Folder 1: 4)
- Oral history interview with Kenneth Holland (KH), 1967 (Folder 1: 5)
- Articles by KH, 1934-1959 (Folder 1: 6)
- Curriculum vitae, 1938 (Folder 1: 7)
- Correspondence and printed matter, 1972-1976 (Folder 1: 8)
- Autobiography and other writings by KH, 1944-1970 (Folder 2: 1)
- Notes on readings and classes, 1933-1934 (Folder 2: 2)
- Correspondence and writings by KH on work camps, 1940-1949 (Folder 2: 3)
- Printed matter relating to international education, 1966-1976 (Folder 2: 4)
- Rockefeller Mission to Latin America, 1969-1970 (Box 2:)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Folder 2: 5)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Folder 3: 1)
  - Correspondence and reports, 1970 (Folder 3: 2)
  - Itineraries, 1969 (Folder 3: 3)
  - Itineraries and schedules, 1969 (Folder 4: 1)
  - Photographs, 1969 (Folder 4: 2)
- Correspondence, 1965-1970 (Folder 4: 3)
- Reports, 1964-1970 (Folder 4: 4)
- Articles by KH, 1944-1967 (Folder 4: 5)
- Draft of book by KH on IIE, 1970 (Folder 5: 1)
- Lecture by KH, 1935 (Folder 5: 2)
- Articles and papers by KH, 1931-1968 (Folder 5: 3)
- Clippings, 1964-1969 (Folder 5: 4)
- Photographs, 1969 (Folder 5: 5)
- Commencement address, 1969 (Folder 5: 6)
- Correspondence and memoranda, 1933-1970 (Box 5:)
  - 1933-1941 (Folder 5: 7)
  - 1962-1970 (Folder 5: 8)
- Printed matter relating to international education, 1950-1977 (Folder 5: 9)
- Scrapbook relating to work camps, 1933-1934 (Folder 6: 1)
- Subject file, 1934-1966 (Box 6:)
  - Personal clippings, 1934-1966 (Folder 6: 2)
  - Notes on readings for classes, 1930-1932 (Folder 6: 3)
  - War, 1931-1934 (Folder 6: 4)
  - Recreation, 1934 (Folder 6: 5)
  - International Student Service, 1934 (Folder 6: 6)
  - Adult education, 1935 (Folder 6: 7)
  - National Student Federation of America, 1935 (Folder 6: 8)
- Correspondence, 1935-1977 (Folder 7: 1)
- Photographs, 1960 (Folder 7: 2)
- IIE Board of Trustees meetings, 1974-1976 (Box 7:)
  - 1974 (Folder 7: 3)
  - 1975 (Folder 7: 4-6)
  - 1976 (Folder 7: 7)
  - 1976 (Folder 8: 1)
  - 1977 (Folder 8: 2)
- Clippings, 1957-1973 (Folder 8: 3)
- Photographs, 1958-1959 (Folder 8: 4)
- Articles and address by KH, 1959-1974 (Folder 8: 5)
- Correspondence, 1934-1977 (Folder 8: 6)
- Clippings, 1955-1964 (Folder 9: 1)
- Photographs, 1960 (Folder 9: 2)
- Notes by KH on trip to Soviet Union, 1959 (Folder 9: 3)
- Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1940-1969 (Box 9:)
  - 1940-1963 (Folder 9: 4)
  - 1964-1969 (Folder 9: 5)
- Paper by KH on international law, 1931 (Folder 10: 1)
- Notes on international law, 1931 (Folder 10: 2-3)
- Notes on Treaty of Versailles, 1931 (Folder 10: 4)
- Short stories by KH, 1930-1935 (Folder 10: 5)
- Harvard East-West Exchange Conference, 1960 (Folder 10: 6)
- Correspondence, 1956-1969 (Folder 10: 7)
- Reports, 1965-1970 (Folder 10: 8)
- Photographs, 1940-1960 (Folder 11: 1)
- Correspondence and memoranda, 1964 (Folder 11: 2)
- Speech, 1969 (Folder 11: 3)
- Letters to the editors of the New York Times and Washington Post, 1961-1964 (Folder 11: 4-9)
- Articles by KH, 1961-1971 (Folder 11: 10-15)
- Other writings by KH, 1933-1971 (Folder 11: 16)
- Notes on Africa, 1970 (Folder 12: 1)
- Rockefeller Mission to Latin America, 1969 (Folder 12:)
  - Schedules and plans, 1969 (Folder 12: 2)
  - Reports, 1969 (Folder 12: 3)
- Articles by KH, 1934-1970 (Folder 13: 1)
- Correspondence and memoranda, 1939-1967 (Box 13:)
  - 1939-1940 (Folder 13: 2)
  - 1967 (Folder 13: 3)
- IIE Board of Trustees meetings, 1973-1977 (Box 13:)
  - 1973 (Folder 13: 4)
  - 1977 (Folder 13: 5)
- Tour of Latin America by U.S. governors, 1959 (Folder 13: 6)
- International Association of Universities seminar, 1974 (Folder 13: 7)
- Articles by KH, 1951-1972 (Folder 13: 8-10)
- Autobiography by KH, 1970 (Folder 14: 1)
- Latin American trip with Dwight Eisenhower, 1960 (Box 14:)
  - Memoranda of conversations, 1960 (Folder 14: 2)
  - Article by KH, 1960 (Folder 14: 3)
  - Materials used for report, 1960 (Folder 14: 4)
  - Notes and pamphlet, 1969 (Folder 14: 5)
- Rockefeller Mission to Latin America, 1969 (Box 14:)
  - Brazil, 1969 (Folder 14: 6)
  - Ecuador, 1969 (Folder 14: 7)
- Articles by KH, 1960-1972 (Folder 15: 1)
- Report on overseas academic programs, 1974 (Folder 15: 2)
- Correspondence, 1977 (Folder 15: 3)
- Articles by KH, 1961-1969 (Folder 15: 4)
- Letter to the editor, New York Herald Tribune, 1965 (Folder 15: 5)
- Reading notes, 1933 (Folder 15: 6)
- Printed matter relating to education, 1943-1975 (Folder 16: 1-12)
- Appointment book, 1964 (Folder 16: 13)
- Notes on meetings, 1969-1972 (Folder 16: 14)
- Edward Murrow Center, 1973 (Folder 16: 15)
- Correspondence, 1949-1976 (Folder 17: 1)
- International Association of Universities seminar, 1974 (Folder 17: 2)
- Writings by KH, 1965-1973 (Folder 17: 3)
- Bicentennial Conference on the United States Constitution, 1976 (Folder 17: 4-6)
- Conference on the Portuguese Educational Reform Program, 1972 (Folder 17: 7)
- Conference on Higher Education in the American Republics, 1970 (Folder 18: 1)
- Writings by KH, 1970 (Folder 18: 2)
- Correspondence, 1972-1977 (Folder 18: 3)
- Biographical material, 1954-1963 (Folder 18: 4)
- Work camps, 1942 (Folder 18: 5)
- Rockefeller Mission to Latin America, 1969 (Box 19:)
  - Clippings and press releases, 1969 (Folder 19: 1)
  - Memoranda, 1969 (Folder 19: 2)
  - Nicaragua, 1969 (Folder 19: 3)
  - Uruguay, 1969 (Folder 19: 4)
  - Memoranda, 1969 (Folder 20: 1)
  - Education, 1969 (Folder 20: 2-3)
- IIE reports, 1964 (Folder 20: 4)
- Retirement of KH, 1971-1972 (Folder 20: 5)
- Student federations, 1928 (Folder 20: 6)
- Council on Higher Education in the American Republics, 1966 (Folder 20: 7)
- Articles and other writings by KH, 1958-1970 (Folder 20: 8)
- Correspondence, 1928-1938 (Folder 20: 9)
- Correspondence with Colonel Müller-Brandenburg, 1936-1937 (Folder 21: 1)
- IIE report by Ralph Tyler, 1954 (Folder 21: 2)
- Tour of the Soviet Union by U.S. governors, 1959 (Folder 21: 3)
- Report on National Youth Administration, 1935 (Folder 21: 4)
- Student paper by KH, 1928 (Folder 21: 5)
- Letter to the editor, New York Times, 1957 (Folder 21: 6)
- Articles by KH, 1959-1961 (Folder 21: 7-9)
- Rockefeller Mission to Latin America, Honduras briefing book, 1969 (Folder 21: 10)
- IIE materials, 1919-1960 (Folder 22:)
  - Annual reports, 1922-1946 (Box 22:)
    - 1922 (Folder 22: 1)
    - 1923 (Folder 22: 2)
    - 1925 (Folder 22: 3)
    - 1926 (Folder 22: 4)
    - 1927 (Folder 22: 5)
    - 1928 (Folder 22: 6)
    - 1929 (Folder 22: 7)
    - 1930 (Folder 22: 8)
    - 1931 (Folder 22: 9)
    - 1933 (Folder 22: 10)
    - 1936 (Folder 22: 11)
    - 1937 (Folder 22: 12)
    - 1938 (Folder 22: 13)
    - 1939 (Folder 22: 14)
    - 1940 (Folder 22: 15)
    - 1941 (Folder 22: 16)
    - 1942 (Folder 22: 17)
    - 1943 (Folder 22: 18)
    - 1944 (Folder 22: 19)
    - 1945 (Folder 22: 20)
    - 1946 (Folder 22: 21)
  - Soviet Union, 1957-1960 (Box 22:)
    - Correspondence on exchanges with U.S., 1957 (Folder 22: 22)
    - Reports on seminars, 1960 (Folder 22: 23)
  - Bulletins and pamphlets, 1919-1947 (Folder 23: 1-60)
  - Bulletins and pamphlets, 1920-1944 (Folder 24: 1-21)
- Correspondence, 1940-1977 (Folder 24: 22)
- Organization of American States special commission meetings, 1962 (Folder 25: 1)
- Civilian Conservation Corps, 1975 (Folder 25: 2)
- Council on Higher Education in the American Republics, 1972 (Folder 25: 3)
- Article by KH, 1972 (Folder 25: 4)
- Lecture by KH, 1975 (Folder 25: 5)
- Correspondence, 1975 (Folder 25: 6)
- Article by KH, 1971 (Folder 25: 7)
- Photograph, 1975 (Folder 25: 8)
- Correspondence, 1943-1963 (Folder 25: 9)
- Printed matter relating to education, 1942-1970 (Folder 26: 1-2)
- Interagency Council on International Educational and Cultural Affairs, 1964 (Folder 26: 3)
- Correspondence, 1940-1977 (Folder 26: 4)
- Rockefeller Mission to Latin America, 1969 (Box 26:)
  - Trinidad and Tobago, 1969 (Folder 26: 5)
  - Dominican Republic, 1969 (Folder 26: 6)
  - Argentina, 1969 (Folder 26: 7)
  - Barbados, 1969 (Folder 26: 8-9)
  - Honduras, 1969 (Folder 27: 1)
  - Haiti, 1969 (Folder 27: 2)
  - Guatemala, 1969 (Folder 27: 3)
  - Colombia, 1969 (Folder 27: 4)
- Photo albums of tour of the Soviet Union by U.S. governors, 1959 (Box 27:)
  - Kiev and environs, 1959 (Folder 27: 5)
  - Alma Ata and Tashkent, 1959 (Folder 28: 1)
  - Leningrad, 1959 (Folder 28: 2)
  - Moscow, 1959 (Folder 28: 3)
- Correspondence, 1949-1973 (Box 29)
  - 1949-1969 (Folder 29: 1)
  - 1970-1973 (Folder 29: 2)
- Seminar on Political Science and the University, Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1967 (Folder 29: 3)
- IIE materials, 1967-1977 (Box 29:)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1967-1976 (Folder 29: 4)
  - Financial statements, 1975 (Folder 29: 5)
  - Board of Trustees meeting, 1977 (Folder 29: 6)
- Bicentennial Conference on the United States Constitution, 1976 (Folder 29: 7)
- Speeches by KH, 1942-1947 (Folder 30: 1)
- Trip to India, 1952-1953 (Folder 30: 2)
- Book outlines, 1963 (Folder 30: 3)
- Posthumous award from Occidental College, 1968 (Folder 30: 4)
- IIE materials, 1973-1977 (Box 30:)
  - Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, 1973-1977 (Folder 30: 5)
  - Printed matter, 1965-1977 (Folder 30: 6)
- Correspondence, 1940-1969 (Folder 30: 7)
- Canadian-United States Educators Conference, 1972 (Folder 31: 1)
- IIE materials, 1963-1968 (Box 31:)
  - Personnel, 1965-1968 (Folder 31: 2)
  - Reports, 1963-1965 (Folder 31: 3)
- Writings by KH, 1941-1967 (Folder 31: 4)
- Correspondence, 1929-1972 (Folder 31: 5)
- Rockefeller Mission to Latin America, 1969-1970 (Box 31)
  - Paraguay, 1969 (Folder 31: 6)
  - Monograph, 1970 (Folder 31: 7)
  - Central America, 1969 (Folder 32: 1)
  - Chile, 1969 (Folder 32: 2)
- Peace Corps, 1961 (Folder 32: 3)
- Latin America, 1962-1963 (Folder 32: 4)
- Articles and speeches by KH, 1935-1948 (Box 33)
  - 1935-1936 (Folder 33: 1)
  - 1936-1948 (Folder 33: 2)
- Personal, 1940 (Folder 33: 3)
- Album of photographs relating to the awarding of an honorary doctorate to KH by Farleigh Dickinson University, 1961 (Folder 33: 4)
- IIE materials, 1967-1975 (Box 33)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1975 (Folder 33: 5)
  - Committee meetings, 1973-1974 (Folder 33: 6)
  - Report on organization, programs, and administration, 1965 (Folder 34: 1)
  - Board of Trustees meeting, 1976 (Folder 34: 2)
  - Correspondence and miscellany, 1965-1975 (Folder 34: 3)
- Personal letters, 1952-1961 (Folder 34: 4)
- Articles and speeches, 1933-1940 (Folder 34: 5-6)
- IIE materials, 1960-1972 (Box 35)
  - Correspondence and miscellany, 1968-1972 (Folder 35: 1)
  - History of the IIE by KH, 1960 (Folder 35: 2)
- Council on Higher Education in the American Republics, 1971-1973 (Folder 35: 3)
- Council on Higher Education for the United States and Canada, 1969 (Folder 35: 4)
- Articles by KH, 1933-1972 (Folder 35: 5)
- Diary and report relating to a trip by KH to the Soviet Union, 1957 (Folder 35: 6)
- Correspondence and reports, 1969-1974 (Folder 35: 7)
- IIE correspondence and reports, 1951-1964 (Folder 36: 1)
- Asian-U.S. Educators Conference, 1970 (Folder 36: 2)
- East Africa visit by KH, 1963 (Folder 36: 3)
- Biographical materials, 1960-1975 (Folder 36: 4)
- Ditchley Foundation, 1967-1968 (Folder 36: 5)
- Rockefeller Mission to Latin America, 1969 (Folder 36: 6-7)
- Clippings, 1949-1962 (Folder 37: 1)
- Photographs, 1959 (Folder 37: 2)
- Articles, papers, and report by KH, 1936-1972 (Folder 37: 3)
- Printed matter, largely relating to education, 1956-1959 (Folder 37: 4)
- Correspondence, 1933-1968 (Folder 37: 5)
- Printed matter, largely relating to education, 1951-1973 (Folder 38: 1-12)
- Article and reports by KH, 1945-1955 (Folder 38: 13)
- Clippings, 1933-1959 (Folder 38: 14)
- Photographs, 1953-1963 (Folder 38: 15)
- Correspondence and miscellany, 1950-1975 (Folder 38: 16)
- Notebooks, 1973-1977 (Folder 39: 1-2)
- Autobiography, 1970 (Folder 39: 3)
- IIE materials, 1949-1975 (Box 39)
  - Charts, 1972 (Folder 39: 4)
  - Reports, 1949-1975 (Folder 39: 5)
- Conference on Higher Education in the Americas, 1970 (Folder 39: 6)
- Writing by KH on Civilian Conservation Corps, 1940 (Folder 40: 1)
- Trip to Portugal, 1972 (Folder 40: 2)
- Ford Foundation, 1970 (Folder 40: 3)
- Federal youth programs, 1970 (Folder 40: 4)
- Personal, 1946-1949 (Folder 40: 5)
- Correspondence, 1951-1973 (Folder 40: 6)
- International education, 1973-1975 (Folder 41: 1)
- Speech by KH, 1956 (Folder 41: 2)
- Student essay by KH and reading notes, 1928 (Folder 41: 3)
- IIE materials, 1953-1974 (Box 41)
  - How They See It, 1953 (Folder 41: 4)
  - History of the IIE, 1969 (Folder 41: 5)
- Board of Trustees meetings, 1973-1974 (Box 41)
  - 1973 (Folder 41: 6)
  - 1974 (Folder 41: 7)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Folder 41: 8)
  - Printed matter, 1969 (Folder 41: 9)
- Federal youth programs, 1970 (Folder 41: 10)
- Correspondence and reports, 1930-1977 (Folder 41: 11)
- Student papers by KH, 1927-1931 (Folder 42: 1)
- Personal letters and papers, 1935-1973 (Folder 42: 2)
- Employment applications and related material, 1946-1950 (Folder 42: 3)
- South Korea, 1965 (Folder 42: 4)
- Rockefeller Mission to Latin America, 1969 (Box 42)
  - Colombia, 1969 (Folder 42: 5)
  - Ecuador, 1969 (Folder 42: 6)
  - Trinidad and Tobago, 1969 (Folder 42: 7)
  - Reports and correspondence, 1969 (Folder 43: 1-3)
  - General statements, 1969 (Folder 44: 1)
  - Country reports, 1969 (Folder 44: 2)
- Latin America, 1962 (Folder 44: 3)
- Student paper by KH, 1936 (Folder 45: 1)
- Doctoral thesis by KH, 1936 (Folder 45: 2)
- Clippings, 1936-1971 (Folder 45: 3)
- IIE materials, 1966-1996 (Box 45:)
  - Board of Trustees meeting, 1996 (Folder 45: 4)
  - Reports, 1969-1982 (Folder 45: 5)
  - Memorandum and reports, 1966-1969 (Folder 45: 6)
- Speech and address by KH, 1971-1973 (Folder 45: 7)
- East Africa trip, 1963 (Folder 45: 8)
- Correspondence, 1934-1972 (Folder 45: 9)
- League of Nations, 1936 (Folder 46: 1)
- Treaty of Versailles, 1930 (Folder 46: 2)
- Articles by KH, 1977 (Folder 46: 3)
- Correspondence and press releases, 1949-1972 (Folder 46: 4)
- Trip to Soviet Union, 1959 (Folder 46: 5)
- France, 1950 (Folder 46: 6)
- Trip to Soviet Union and Poland, 1957 (Folder 47: 1)
- History of student exchanges, 1970 (Folder 47: 2)
- Speech and article by KH, 1967-1977 (Folder 47: 3)
- Photographs, 1942-1950 (Folder 47: 4)
- IIE materials, 1962-1990 (Box 47)
  - Board of Trustees meeting, 1974 (Folder 47: 5)
  - Reports, 1962-1990 (Folder 47: 6)
- Correspondence, 1970-1977 (Folder 47: 7)
- Printed matter relating to education, 1970-1975 (Folder 47: 8-9)
- Study of Civilian Conservation Corps, 1941 (Folder 48: 1)
- Rockefeller Mission to Latin America, 1969 (Box 48)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Folder 48: 2)
  - Itineraries and schedules, 1969 (Folder 48: 3)
  - Argentina, 1969 (Folder 48: 4)
  - Mexico, 1969 (Folder 48: 5)
- Writings by KH, 1970-1980 (Folder 48: 6)
- Correspondence, 1955-1977 (Folder 48: 7)
- Student exchange programs, 1976-1977 (Folder 48: 8)
- Rockefeller Mission to Latin America, 1969 (Box 49:)
  - Itineraries and schedules, 1969 (Folder 49: 1)
  - Brazil, 1969 (Folder 49: 2)
- American Council on Education annual meeting, 1975 (Folder 49: 3)
- Certificate from U.S. Department of State, 1950 (Folder 49: 4)
- History of the IIE, 1954-1955 (Folder 49: 5)
- Autobiography, 1970 (Folder 49: 6)
- Speech by KH, 1933 (Folder 49: 7)
- Address by KH, 1977 (Folder 49: 8)
- Articles by KH, 1934-1937 (Folder 49: 9)
- Clippings, 1940-1960 (Folder 50: 1)
- Seminar on Latin American universities, 1973 (Folder 50: 2)
- Photographs, 1941-1960 (Folder 50: 3)
- Writings by KH, 1960-1966 (Folder 50: 4)
- Programs and invitations, 1942-1961 (Folder 50: 5)
- Correspondence, 1937-1955 (Folder 50: 6)
- Bird, Remsen D., 1938-1941 (Folder 51: 1)
- Clippings, 1945-1963 (Folder 51: 2)
- Article by KH, 1958 (Folder 51: 3)
- Exchanges with the Soviet Union, 1956 (Folder 51: 4)
- Programs, 1936-1957 (Folder 51: 5)
- Conference on Higher Education in the Americas, 1970 (Folder 51: 6)
- IIE materials, 1949-1975 (Box 51)
  - Invitation and bulletin, 1949-1955 (Folder 51: 7)
  - Reports, 1969-1975 (Folder 51: 8)
- Identity card, 1931 (Folder 51: 9)
- Photograph, 1960 (Folder 51: 10)
- Correspondence, 1934-1975 (Folder 51: 11)
- Printed matter relating to education, 1969-1975 (Folder 51: 12-15)
- Autobiography, 1970-1974 (Folder 52: 1)
- Correspondence and memoranda, 1970-1974 (Folder 52: 2)
- Speeches by KH, 1939-1974 (Box 52)
  - 1939 (Folder 52: 3)
  - 1939-1940 (Folder 52: 4)
  - 1941 (Folder 52: 5)
  - 1974 (Folder 52: 6)
- Photograph, 1950 (Folder 52: 7)
- Articles by KH, 1933-1937 (Folder 52: 8)
- Correspondence, 1940-1941 (Folder 52: 9)
- Correspondence and memoranda, 1975-1976 (Folder 53: 1)
- Trip to Soviet Union, 1957 (Folder 53: 2)
- Rockefeller Foundation, 1965 (Folder 53: 3)
- IIE officers' retreat, 1964 (Folder 53: 4)
- Response to speech by President Johnson, 1965 (Folder 53: 5)
- Speeches by KH, 1959-1974 (Box 53:)
  - 1959 (Folder 53: 6)
  - 1969 (Folder 53: 7)
  - 1970 (Folder 53: 8)
  - 1971 (Folder 53: 9)
  - 1974 (Folder 53: 10)
- Notebooks, 1957 (Folder 53: 11)
- Notes, 1960-1970 (Folder 53: 12)
- Articles and speeches by KH, 1946-1963 (Folder 54: 1-2)
- Speeches by KH, 1953-1972 (Box 54:)
  - 1953 (Folder 54: 3)
  - 1954 (Folder 54: 4-9)
  - 1959 (Folder 54: 10-12)
  - 1960 (Folder 54: 13-15)
  - 1961 (Folder 54: 16-17)
  - 1962 (Folder 54: 18)
  - 1972 (Folder 54: 19-20)
- Article by KH, 1937 (Folder 55: 1)
- Speeches by KH, 1955-1967 (Box 55:)
  - 1955 (Folder 55: 2-6)
  - 1955-1956 (Folder 55: 7)
  - 1956 (Folder 55: 8-11)
  - 1957 (Folder 55: 12-14)
  - 1958 (Folder 55: 15-16)
  - 1959 (Folder 55: 17-19)
  - 1964 (Folder 55: 20-21)